Register of the United States Army European Command, Historical Division Typescript Studies, 1945-1954
Hoover Institution Archives
- B Series Manuscripts. (Box 5-28)
  - B-547 Fifteenth Army Artillery (Mar.-Apr. 1945) and Fifth Panzer Army Artillery (18 Mar. 1944-Feb. 1945). By Generalleutnant Richard Metz; 126 pp, 2 illus. (Box 21)
  - B-548 LVIII Panzer Corps.(15 Sep.-5 Nov. 1944). By General der Panzertruppen Walter Krueger; 28 pp, 1 illus; 1947. (Box 21)
  - B-549 LXXIV Corps (22 Mar.-16 Apr. 1945). By General der lnfanterie Carl Puechler; 22 pp, 5 illus; 1947. (Box 21)
  - B-550 LXIV Corps (6 Dec. 1944-28 Jan. 1945). By General der I nfanterie Helmuth Thumm; 13 pp; 1947. (Box 21)
  - B-551 Wehrkreis IV (1 Feb.-10 Apr. 1945). By General der lnfanterie Hans- Wolfgang Reinhard; 12 pp, 4 illus; 1947. Dresden area: (Box 21)
  - B-552 Army Group G (May-Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Heinz von Gyldenfeldt; 16 pp. (Box 21)
  - B-553 St. Nazaire Naval Forces (Normandy). By Konteradmira; Hans Mirow; 7 pp, 7 illus; 1947. (Box 21)
  - B-554 Wehrkreis XII (31 Mar.-12 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Ernst Faeckenstedt; 21 pp, 4 illus; 1947. (Box 21)
  - B-555 Airborne Operations in Holland (Sep.-Nov.1944). By The Dutch Historical Section; 5 pp, 3 illus; 1947. (Box 21)
  - B-556 Toulon, Naval Commander (21 Apr.-28 Aug. 1944). By Konteradmiral Heinrich Ruhfus; 31 pp, 2 illus; 1947. Defense of Toulon. (Box 21)
  - B-557 198th Infantry Division (25 Jun.-15 Aug. 1944). By Generalmajor Otto Richter; 28 pp; 1947. Unit rehabilation; coastal defense. (Box 21)
  - B-559 LXIV Cops (22 Dec. 1944-12 Jan. 1945). By Oberst Paul Koehler; 15 pp, 1 illus. Operation SOLSTICE (southern Alsace). (Box 21)
  - B-560 Historical Section, OKH (1919-1945). By. Generalmajor Ludwig Ruedt von Collenberg; 10 pp; 1946. Activities; duties of the Deputy Chief of General Staff V. (Box 21)
  - B-561 326th Volks Grenadier Division (26 Jan.-17 Apr. 1945). By to Generalmajor Erwin Kaschner; 2 vols, 30 pp, 7 illus; 1947. (Box 21)
  - B-562 (Box 21)
  - B-563 347th Infantry Division (15 Sep.-15 Nov. 1944). By Generalleutnant Wolf Trierenberg; 14 pp, 4 illus; 1947. (Box 21)
  - B-564 LXIV Corps (10 Feb.-4 Apr. 1945). General der Artillerie Max Grimmeis; 15 pp, 3 illus; 1947. (Box 21)
  - B-565 Corps Merker (12-23 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Ludwig Merker; 51 pp, 5 illus; 1947. Improvisations and delaying actions. (Box 21)
  - B-566* WehrmachtCommander Karlsruhe (15 Sep. 1944-21 Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor Walther Hossfeld; 15 pp, 12 illus; 1947. (Not translated- 1954.) (Box 21)
  - B-567 Wehrmacht Commander Karlsruhe (22 Mar.-6 May 1945). By Generalmajor Walther Hossfeld; 8 pp, 1 illus, 1 map; 1947. Preparations for the defense of the Karlsruhe area. (Box 21)
  - B-568 Wehrkreis IX-Situation (2 Apr. 1945). By General der Artillerie Maximilian Fretter-Pico; 8 pp, 4 illus; 1947. (Box 21)
  - B-569 Wehrkreis IX (3-22 Apr. 1945). By General der Adillerie Maximilian Fretter-Pico; 24 pp; 1947. From Kassel to the Harz Mountains. (Box 21)
  - B-570 271st Infantry Division (Jan.-May 1944). By Generalleutnant Paul Danhauser; 14 pp, 3 illus; 1947. Coastal defense in southern France; details on construction of field fortifications. (Box 21)
  - B-571 LXXXV Corps Artillery (24 Oct.-15 Nov.1944). By Generalmajor Walter Beisswaenger; 7 pp, 4 illus; 1947. (Box 21)
  - B-572 2d Parachute Division (20 Dec. 1944-2 Mar. 1945). By Generalleutnant Walter Lackner; 3pp, 1 illus; 1947. (Box 21)
  - B-573 416th Infantry Division (5 Oct. 1944-17 Feb. 1945). By Oberstleutnant i.G. Karl Redmer; 54 pp, 5 illus; 1947. Defense of permanent fortifications between the Moselle and the Saar. (Box 21)
  - B-574 Army Group B Artillery (22 Mar.-17 Apr. 1945). By General der Artillerie Karl Thoholte; 3 pp, 1 illus; 19467. (Box 21)
  - B-575 Nineteenth Army Artillery (4 Apr.-18 Aug.1944). By Generalmajor Walter Vogel; 78 pp, 11 illus; 1947. French Mediterranean coast, 1943- 44. Of historical and technical interest. (Box 21)
  - B-576 LXXXI Corps (25 Jan.-21 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie Friedrich Koechling; 67 pp, 9 illus. Combat on both banks of the lower Rhine (Cologne). (Box 21)
  - B- 577 ISS Panzer Corps (15 Oct.-16 Dec. 1944). By Oberst der Waffen-SS Rudolf Lehmann; 13 pp, 3 illus; 1946. Ardennes offensive; preparation and assembly. (Box 22)
  - B-579 471st Administrative Division (23 Mar.-5 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Ernst Haeckel; 18 pp, 4 illus; 1947. (Box 22)
  - B-580 6th Parachute Division (1 Apr.-10 May 1945). By Generalmajor Rudolf Langhaeuser; 12 pp, 2 illus; 1947. (Box 22)
  - B-581 Eleventh Army (1-23 Apr. 1945). By Oberst Fritz Estor; 52 pp, 9 illus; 1947. (Box 22)
  - B-582 Strategic Survey, Worldwide. By General der Infanterie G. Blumentritt; 62 pp; 1947. Reflections on the current world situation. (See also MS # B-635). (Box 22)
  - B-583 Army Group G (4 Apr.-3 May 1945). By General der Infanterie Friedr. Schultz; 7 pp; 1946. (Box 22)
  - B-584 LXXXIX Corps (18-28 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie Gustav Hoehne; 8 pp, 2 illus; 1947. (Box 22)
  - B-585 Battle Group Alberti (1-28 Apr. 1945) and Wehrkreis XII South (15- 25 Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor Konrad von Alberti; 14 pp, 2 illus; 1947. (Box 22)
  - B-586 6th SS Mountain Division (26 Jan.-28 Feb. 1945). By SSGruppenfuehrer Karl Brenner; 5 pp, 5 illus; 1947. Northern Alsace. (Box 22)
  - B-587 Propaganda. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blummentritt; 17 pp; Hist Division EUCOM mimeograph, Vol. 1, No. 15; 1952. A study of propaganda in peace and war. (Box 22)
  - B-588 Army Group G (May-Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Heinz von Gyldenfeldt; 18 pp. Withdrawal to the Moselle. (Box 22)
  - B-589 Army Group G (15-25 Sep. 1944). By Gernalleutnant Heinz von Gyldenfeldt; 20 pp; 1947. (Box 22)
  - B-590 11th Panzer Division (6-21 Mar. 1945). By Generalleutnant Wend von Wietersheim; 11 pp, 2 illus; 1946. (Box 22)
  - B-591 159th Infantry Division (16 Sep.-1 Dec. 1944). By Generalmajor Friedrich Dernen; 14 pp, 3 illus; 1947. Belfort Gap. (Box 22)
  - B-593 Army Group B (22 Mar.-17 Apr. 1945). By Generalmajor Carl Wagener; 8 pp, 7 illus; 1946. A clear account of this army's operations. near the end of the war. Includes comments on strategy and tactics. (Box 22)
  - B-594 Seventh Army Artillery (Ardennes, Parts II and III). By Generalmajor Paul Riedel; 12 pp. (Box 22)
  - B-595 559th Volks Grenadier Division (21 Mar.-21 Apr. 1945). By Generalmajor Kurt von Muehlen; 6 pp, 3 illus; 1947. (Box 22)
  - B-596 LXVII Corps (1 Jun.-14 Sep. 1944). By Oberstleutnant i.G. Kurt Gerber; 68 pp, 6 illus. Northern France and Belgium; problems of coast defense. (Box 22)
  - B-597 III Flak Corps (May-14 Sep. 1944). By General der Flakartillerie Wolfgang Pickert; 42 pp, 4 illus; 1947. Normandy; of historical and technical interest. (Box 22)
  - B-598 LXIV Corps (4-22 Apr. 1945). By General der Artillerie Max Grimmeis; 46 pp, 1 illus; 1947. East of the Rhine. (Box 22)
  - B-599 465 Replacement and Training Division (22 Mar.-11 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Curt Hoffmann; 9 pp, 4 illus; 1947. Wuerttemberg. (Box 22)
  - B-600* Army Group G (25 Jan.-21 Mar. 1945). By Generaloberst (Waffen-SS) Paul Hausser; 30 pp; 1947. By the army group commander. (Box 22)
  - B-601 LXVII Panzer Corps (27 Jan.-7 Mar. 1945). By Oberstleutnant i.G. Douglas von Bernstorff; 45 pp, 8 illus; 1947. West of the lower Rhine. (Box 22)
  - B-602 47th Volks Grenadier Division (1 Oct. 1944-5 Jan. 1945). By Generalleutnant Max Bork; 16 pp, 1 illus; 1947. Third Battle of Aachen. (Box 22)
  - B-603 352d Volks Grenadier Division (19 Freb.-21 Mar. 1945). By to Generalmajor Erich Schmidt; 2 vols, 26 pp, 7 illus; 1947. Eifel Mountains (Box 22)
  - B-604 area. (Box 22)
  - B-605 LVIII Panzer Corps Artillery (6 Feb.-5 Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor Gerhard Triepel, 5 pp; 1947. (Box 22)
  - B-606 Twelfth Army (12 Apr.-7 May 1945). By Oberst Guenther Reichhelm; 40 pp, 4 illus; 1947. On the Elbe River. (Box 22)
  - B-169). By Vizeadmiral Friedrich Frisius; 8 pp. (Box 23)
  - B-607 LXVI Corps (4-20 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Hermann Floerke; 28 pp, 3 illus; 1947. Central Germany. (Box 23)
  - B-608 198th Reserve Infantry Division (Jul.-Oct. 1944). By Generalleutnant Walter Botsch; 2 pp; 1947. Southern France. (Box 23)
  - B-609 560th Volks Grenadier Division (5 Feb.-9 Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor Rudolf Bader; 10 pp, 2 illus; 1947. Defense of the Trier area. (Box 23)
  - B-610 277th Infantry Division (13 Aug.-8 Sep. 1944). By Generalmajor Wilhelm Viebig; 20 pp; 1946. Normandy. (Box 23)
  - B-612 Military Commander France (Jul.-Sep. 1944). By Generalmajor Ernst von Krause; 7 pp; 1947. Report on the ineffective construction of the Somme-Swiss border defense line. (Box 23)
  - B-613 St. Nazaire Supply (20 Aug. 1944-10 May 1945). By Vizeadmiral Withold Rothe; 7 pp; 1947. (Box 23)
  - B-614 LXXXI Corps (22 Mar.-13 Apr. 1945). By General der Infanterie Friedrich Koechling; 42 pp, 3 illus; 1947. East of the Rhine; summary of the general situation of German troops during the last months of the war. (Box 23)
  - B-615 172d Administrative Division (28-29 Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor Hans Boelsen; 4 pp, 2 illus; 1947. Central Germany (Vogelsberg). (Box 23)
  - B-616 36th Volks Grenadier Division (28 Mar.-3 May 1945). By Generalmajor Helmut Kleikamp; 20 pp; 1947. Bavaria. (Box 23)
  - B-617 LXXXV Corps (29 Mar.-7 May 1945). By General der Panzertruppen Smilo von Luettwitz; 27 pp, 10 illus; 1947. Central and southern Germany. (Box 23)
  - B-618 18th Luftwaffe Field Division (18 Aug.-3 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Joachim von Treskow; 17 pp, 2 illus; 1947. Northern France. (Box 23)
  - B-619 Operations in Brittany near Lorient. By Generalmajor Julius Kuse; 16 pp; 1947. Answers to a questionnaire; the counterattack on Vannes, 4-6 Aug. 1944. (Box 23)
  - B-620 II Air Force Corps (Jan.-28 Jun. 1944). By General der Flieger Alfred Buelowius; 43 pp. The air situation during the invasion. (Box 23)
  - B-621 716th Infantry Division (1943-28 Jun. 1944). By Generalleutnant Wilhelm Richter; 69 pp, 4 illus; 1947. Normandy; a report by the commander of the division hit by the British main effort in the first two days of the invasion. (Box 23)
  - B-622 IV Luftwaffe Field Corps (Jul. 1943-10 Sept. 1944). By General der Infanterie Erich Petersen; 7 pp, 1 illus; 1947. Questionnaire on southern France. (Box 23)
  - B-623 I SS Panzer Corps (16 Aug.-18 Oct. 1944). By General der Waffen-SS Georg Keppler; 45 pp; 1947. Northern France; the West Wall; around Aachen. (Box 23)
  - B-624 Supplement to Comments on Report by Admiral Krancke (MSS # B-341 (Box 23)
  - B-625 256th Volks Grenadier Division (20 Mar.-8 Apr. 1945). By Oberstleutnant i.G. Bernhard Koegel; 16 pp, 1 illus; 1947. From the Main River to the Saale River (Franconia). (Box 23)
  - B-626 361st Volks Grenadier Division (31 Aug.-16 Dec. 1944). By Generalmajor Alfred Philippi; 66 pp, 5 illus; 1947. Lorraine and the Northern Vosges. (Box 23)
  - B-627 Volkssturm (Oct. 1944-Apr. 1945). By Generalmajor Hans Kissel; 27 pp, 1 illus; 1947. (Box 23)
  - B-628 An Airborne Panzer Corps. By Generalleutnant Wilhelm Schmalz; 15 pp, 5 sketches, 1 photograph; OCMH multilith; German Report Series; 1948. Organization of Panzer Corps "Hermann Goering" during the last part of the war; views on the organization of airborne armored forces. (Box 23)
  - B-629 Himmler's Field Staff (1941-44). By Generalmajor Ernst Rode; 14 pp; 1947. Police organization in occupied enemy territory. (Box 23)
  - B-630 277th Infantry Division (Jan.-24 Jul. 1944). By Oberstleutnant i.G. Horst von Wangenheim; 52 pp, 2 illus; 1947. Battle experiences of a frontline division. (Box 23)
  - B-631 21st Panzer Division (28 Jul.-14 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Edgar Feuchtinger; 34 pp. (Box 23)
  - B-632 German Division Numbering System. By Oberstleutnant i.G. Kurt Gerber; 4 pp; 1947. (Box 23)
  - B-635 World Situation. By General der Infanterie G. Blumentritt; 49 pp; 1947. A supplement to MS # B-582. (Box 23)
  - B-636 Capture of U.S. V Corps Operations Plan on 7 Jun. 1944. By Oberstleutnant Fritz Ziegelmann; 2 pp; 1947. Comment on German failure to exploit this information. (Box 23)
  - B-637 V Corps (U.S.) Operations Plan--OB West. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 8 pp; 1947. Reaction of OB West to the capture of the U.S. V Corps operations plan. (Box 23)
  - B-638 Capture of Corinthian Isthmus by Airborne Attack. By Generalleutnant Ruediger von Heyking; 7 pp; 1947. (Box 23)
  - B-639 2d Special Bomber Wing in the Crete Operation. By Generalleutnant Ruediger von Heyking; 10 pp; 1947. (Box 23)
  - B-642 VIII Air Corps in Greece. By General der Flieger Rudolf Meister; 62 pp; 1947. (Box 23)
  - B-645 Logistics and Economics of Occupation of Greece. By Generalstabsintendant Alb. Piske; 79 pp; 1947. The administrative operations of the Air Force command in Greece, 1941-43; includes a discussion of occupation problems. (Box 23)
  - B-646 Capture of Crete (May 1941). By General der Gebirgstruppen Julius Ringel; 105 pp; 7 illus. A thorough account of the operation. (Box 23)
  - B-647 Thoughts of a Former Soldier on Strategy, Politics, and Psychology of the 1939-45 War. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 77 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. (Box 23)
  - B-648 Training--Premilitary. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 16 pp; 1947. (Box 23)
  - B-650 Training--Reserve Officers (Peacetime). By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 17 pp; 1947. (Box 23)
  - B-651 Training Regular Officers in Peacetime. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 68 pp; 1947. Based on German methods and the opinions of the author. (Box 24)
  - B-652 Effect of Fortifications on Strategic Planning. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 54 pp, 6 illus; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-653 Strategic Untenability of Fortified Lines. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 102 pp; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-655 Miscellaneous Military Problems. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 43 pp; 1947. Command; organization; training; armament. (Box 24)
  - B-656 U.S. V Corps Operations Plan--Seventh Army. By Generalleutnant Max Pemsel; 4 pp; 1947. (See MS # B-636.) (Box 24)
  - B-657 Armed Forces Headquarters--Theoretical Organization. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 29 pp; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-658 Reconnaissance. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 21 pp. (Box 24)
  - B-659 Artillery Preparation for the Attack. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 16 pp; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-660 Is the Enemy Defeated? Can the Situation be Exploited? By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 19 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. Problems in estimating the enemy situation. (Box 24)
  - B-661 Wartime Alliances. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 24 pp; OCMH Multilith; 1947. Evaluation of and cooperation with military allies. (Box 24)
  - B-662 The Inhumanity of Modern Warfare. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 9 pp; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-663 Coast Artillery--Atlantic Wall. By Generalleutnant Ernst Goettke; 14 pp; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-664 Military Commander, France--Signals (5 Nov. 1943-31 Aug. 1944). By Generalleutnant Eugen Oberhaeuser; 16 pp. Of technical and historical interest. (Box 24)
  - B-665 Wehrkreis VI and Wehrkreis XII (Jan. 1944-Mar. 1945). By Generalleutnant Ernst Faeckenstedt; 28 pp; 1947. Organization and improvisation under emergency conditions. (Box 24)
  - B-666 II SS Panzer Corps Artillery (15 Jun.-24 Jul. 1944). By SS Generalmajor Friedrich W. Bock; 11 pp; 1947. Normandy. (Box 24)
  - B-668 Atlantic Wall--Invasion Sector (Jun. 1943-Jan. 1944). By Generalleutnant Rudolf Schmetzer; 29 pp; 1947. A study by an expert on fortifications. (Box 24)
  - B-669 Atlantic Wall, Effect of Bombing and Naval Artillery. By Generalleutnant Rudolf Schmetzer; 32 pp; 1947. The effects of bombs and heavy naval guns on the Atlantic Wall fortifications. A study by an expert on fortifications. (Box 24)
  - B-671 Organization Todt--Operations in West. By Diplomingenieur Xaver Dorsch; 17 pp, 2 illus; 1947. A supplement to MS # B-670. (Box 24)
  - B-673 XLVII Panzer Corps (11 Jun.-27 Jul. 1944). By General der Panzertruppen H. von Luettwitz; 5 pp; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-674 II Parachute Corps (10 Mar.-5 May 1945). By General der Fallschirmtruppen Eugen Meindl; 19 pp; 1947. From the Rhine to Holstein. (Box 24)
  - B-675 Army Group B--Intelligence Estimate (1 Jun. 1944). By Oberst i.G. Anton Staubwasser; 23 pp; 1947. (See also MSS # B-782 and B-825.) (Box 24)
  - B-676 Sixth Panzer Army (Oct. 1944-24 Jan. 1945). By Oberst Guenther Reichhelm; 11 pp; 1947. In the Ardennes. Comment on MS # A-924. (Box 24)
  - B-677 Luftwaffe Ground Organization, France (Jun.-Jul. 1944). By Generalmajor Erwin Notti; 17 pp. (Box 24)
  - B-680 17th Luftwaffe Field Division (25 Jul.-1 Sep. 1944). By Oberst i.G. Elmar Warning and Generalleutnant Hans Hoecker; 59 pp, 1 illus; 1946. (Box 24)
  - B-682 "Impossible" Situations. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 11 pp; 1947. Examples from operations in Russia, 1941. (Box 24)
  - B-683 Operations in Darkness and Smoke. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 26 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-684 War in the Rear Communications Zone. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 10 pp, 1 illus; 1947. Partisan warfare in Russia. (Box 24)
  - B-686 Value of Military History. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 12 pp; 1947. Methods of teaching military history. (Box 24)
  - B-687 The Methods of Warfare and the Number of Casualties. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 15 pp; 1947. How to reduce casualties in modern warfare. Not a statistical study. (Box 24)
  - B-688 18th Volks Grenadier Division (1 Sep. 1944-25 Jan. 1945). By Obersleutnant i.G. Dietrich Moll; 116 pp, 3 illus, Hist. Div. USAREUR mimeograph; 1953. Of tactical and technical interest. (Box 24)
  - B-689 V-Weapons Tactics (LXV Corps). By Oberst i.G. Eugen Walter; 98 pp, 4 illus; 1947. The development and use of V-weapons; includes little technical data. B690 The Main Line of Resistance. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 15 pp; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-691 Military Revolutions. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 23 pp; 1947. Causes and effects of revolutionary movements within armed forces. (Box 24)
  - B-693 6th SS Mountain Division (1-19 Mar. 1945). By Generalleutnant Karl Brenner; 12 pp; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-694 First Army (26 Apr.-8 May 1945). By Generalmajor Wolf Hauser; 6 pp, 3 illus; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-695 245th Infantry Division (27 Dec. 1944-15 Jan. 1945). By Oberst Werner Wagner; 15 pp; 1947. Operations around Wissembourg. (Box 24)
  - B-696 Nineteenth Army (13 Aug.-15 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Walter Botsch; 98 pp, 9 illus; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-697 Why Germany was Defeated in Two World Wars. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 21 pp; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-698 Tactical Organization of Troops: An Historical Review. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 50 pp; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-699 "Ideas" and Military History. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 21 pp; 1947. (Box 24)
  - B-703 Army Group G (22 Mar.-6 May 1945). By Oberst i.G. Horst Wilutzky; 61 pp, 16 illus. Last resistance in central and southern Germany. (Box 25)
  - B-705 Advance Elements and Combat Outposts. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 10 pp; 1947. A theoretical study. (Box 25)
  - B-712 Deceptions and Errors in War. By General der Infanterie Guenther Blumentritt; 30 pp; OCMH multilith; 1947. A theoretical study. (Box 25)
  - B-715 6th SS Mountain Division (19 Mar.-3 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant der Waffen-SS Karl Brenner; 13 pp, 6 illus; 1947. On and east of the Rhine. (Box 25)
  - B-716 Wehrmacht Losses. By Professor Percy E. Schramm; 35 pp. A statistical study based on official German documents. Includes data on production and losses of aircraft, tanks, submarines, and other weapons. (Box 25)
  - B-717 Army Group H (1 Nov. 1944-31 Jan. 1945) and First Parachute Army (4 Sep.-31 Oct. 1944). By Generaloberst Kurt Student; 22 pp; 1947. Fighting on the Albert Canal and at Arnhem; the formation of Army Group H. Comments on MS # B-147. (Box 25)
  - B-720 Rommel's Views (1 Apr.-May 1944). By Generalleutnant Dr. Hans Speidel; 24 pp; 1947. With a commentary by General der Panzertruppen Leo Geyr von Schweppenburg. The theory behind troop dispositions in France. (Box 25)
  - B-721 Rommel and 20 July (15 Apr.-14 Oct. 1944). By Generalleutnant Dr. Hans Speidel; 14 pp; 1947. The role of Field Marshal Rommel in attempts to achieve an independent termination of the war in the West prior to 20 July 1944. (Box 25)
  - B-722 The Campaign in Northern France-Vol. I (25 Jul.-14 Sep. 1944). By Generalmajor Rudolf Freiherr von Gersdorff; 34 pp, 3 illus. Situation at Saint-Lo. See also MS # B-249 and B-723 - B-730; these nine studies provide an overall picture of the war of movement and the withdrawal to the German border. (Box 25)
  - B-723 Northern France-Vol. II: Breakthrough to Avranches (25-31 Jul. 1944). By Generalmajor Rudolf Freiherr von Gersdorff; 38 pp; 1947. The American breakthrough. (Box 25)
  - B-725 Northern France-Vol. IV: Avranches Counterattack (1-11 Aug. 1944). By Generalmajor Rudolf Freiherr von Gersdorff; 64 pp, 4 illus; 1946. (Box 25)
  - B-726 Northern France-Vol. V: Fifth Panzer Army (25 Jul.-25 Aug. 1944). By Generalmajor Rudolf Freiherr von Gersdorff; 37 pp, 3 illus. (Box 25)
  - B-727 Northern France-Vol. VI: Falaise-Argentan Pocket. By Generalmajor R. von Gersdorff; 61pp, 2 illus; 1946. (Box 25)
  - B-728 Northern France-Vol. VII: First Army (11 Aug.-15 Sep. 1944), By Oberst i. G. Albert Emmerich; 28 pp, 9 illus; 1946. In the Paris area; retreat toward Lorraine. (Box 25)
  - B-730 Northern France-Vol. X: Seventh Army (1-20 Sep. 1944). By General der Panzertruppen Erich Brandenberger; 111 pp, 7 illus; 1947. Seventh Army in Belgium; retreat to the West Wall. (Box 25)
  - B-732 First Army Organization and Replacements (11 Aug.-15 Sep. 1944). By Major Kurt Hold; 24 pp; 5 illus; 1947. Emergency organization and improvisations. (Box 25)
  - B-735 XII SS Corps (3 Mar.-16 Apr. 1945) Conclusions. By Oberst i. G. Ulrich Ulms; 20 pp. Improvised defense against overwhelming enemy forces. (Box 25)
  - B-736 12th Infantry Division (1 Mar.-14 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Gerhard Engel; 12 pp; 1947. (Box 25)
  - B-738 LXX Corps (6 Jun.-11 Aug. 1944). By General der Artillerie Curt Gallenkamp; 43, pp; 1948. South of the Loire, from the invasion to 10 August 1944; includes comments on coast defense. (Box 25)
  - B-739 XII SS Corps (23 Feb.-3 Mar. 1945). By Major i. G. Karl Reuther. 85 pp; 9 illus; 1947. Between the Roer and Rhine Rivers. Continued in MS # (Box 25)
  - B-740 The Ardennes Offensive: A Critique. By General der Infanterie G. Blumentritt; 23 pp; 1948. (Box 25)
  - B-745 Nineteenth Army (1 Apr.-6 May 1945). By General der Panzertruppen Erich Brandenberger; 175 pp, 21 illus; 1948. The final battles. (Box 26)
  - B-747 II SS Panzer Corps (14 Jun.-5 Jul. 1944). By General der Waffen-SS Wilhelm Bittrich; 9 pp. In Normandy. (Box 26)
  - B-748 II SS Panzer Corps (15 Jul.-5 Sep. 1944). By General der Wafferf-SS to Wilhelm Bittrich; 2 vols,15 pp; 1947-48. (Box 26)
  - B-749 (Box 26)
  - B-751 First Army (7 Nov.-4 Dec. 1944). By Oberst Willy Mantey; 47 pp, 7 illus; 1947. A critical survey of events. (Box 26)
  - B-752 XII SS Corps (23 Feb.-3 Mar. 1945). By Major i.G. Karl Reuther; 33 pp. Defense of the Roer; continuation of MS # B-739. (Box 26)
  - B-757 Fifth Panzer Army (14 Sep.-15 Oct. 1944). By General der Pahzertruppen Hasso von Manteuffel; 4 pp; 1947. West of the Vosges. (Box 26)